[
    {
        "id":1,
        "question":"What is a correct syntax to output \"Hello World\" in Python?",
        "answers":[
            "p(\"Hello World\")",
            "echo \"Hello World\"",
            "print(\"Hello World\")",
            "echo(\"Hello World\");"],
        "correctAnswer":"print(\"Hello World\")"
    },
    {
        "id":2,
        "question":"How do you insert COMMENTS in Python code?",
        "answers":[
            "#This is a comment",
            "/*This is a comment*/",
            "//This is a comment"],
        "correctAnswer":"#This is a comment"
    },
    {
        "id":3,
        "question":"Which one is NOT a legal variable name?",
        "answers":[
             "Myvar",
             "_myvar",
             "my_var",
             "my-var"],
        "correctAnswer":"my-var"
    },
    {
        "id":4,
        "question":"How do you create a variable with the numeric value 5?",
        "answers":[
            "x = 5",
            "x = int(5)",
            "Both the other answers are correct"],
        "correctAnswer":"Both the other answers are correct"
    },
    {
        "id":5,
        "question":"What is the correct file extension for Python files?",
        "answers":[
            ".pyth",
            ".py",
            ".pyt",
            ".pt"],
        "correctAnswer":".py"
    },
    {
        "id":6,
        "question":"How do you create a variable with the floating number 2.8?",
        "answers":[
            "x = 2.8",
            "Both the other answers are correct",
            "x = float(2.8)"],
        "correctAnswer":"Both the other answers are correct"
    },
    {
        "id":7,
        "question":"What is the correct syntax to output the type of a variable or object in Python?",
        "answers":[
            "print(typeOf(x))",
            "print(type(x))",
            "print(typeof(x))",
            "print(typeof x)"
        ],
        "correctAnswer":"print(type(x))"
    },
    {
        "id":8,
        "question":"What is the correct way to create a function in Python?",
        "answers":[
            "function myfunction():",
            "def myFunction():",
            "create myFunction():"],
        "correctAnswer":"def myFunction():"
    },
    {
        "id":9,
        "question":"In Python, 'Hello', is the same as \"Hello\"",
        "answers":[
            "False",
            "True"],
        "correctAnswer":"True"
    },
    {
        "id":10,
        "question":"What is a correct syntax to return the first character in a string?",
        "answers":[
            "x = \"Hello\"[0]",
            "x = sub(\"Hello\", 0, 1)",
            "x = \"Hello\".sub(0, 1)"],
        "correctAnswer":"x = \"Hello\"[0]"
    },
    {
        "id":11,
        "question":"Which method can be used to remove any whitespace from both the beginning and the end of a string?",
        "answers":[
            "len()",
            "ptrim()",
            "trim()",
            "strip()"],
        "correctAnswer":"strip()"
    },
    {
        "id":12,
        "question":"Which method can be used to return a string in upper case letters?",
        "answers":[
            "upper()",
            "toUpperCase()",
            "uppercase()",
            "upperCase()"],
        "correctAnswer":"upper()"
    },
    {
        "id":13,
        "question":"Which method can be used to replace parts of a string?",
        "answers":[
            "replace()",
            "repl()",
            "switch()",
            "replaceString()"],
        "correctAnswer":"replace()"
    },
    {
        "id":14,
        "question":"Which operator is used to multiply numbers?",
        "answers":[
            "*",
            "x",
            "#",
            "%"],
        "correctAnswer":"*"
    },
    {
        "id":15,
        "question":"Which operator can be used to compare two values?",
        "answers":[
            "=",
            "<>",
            "><",
        "=="],
        "correctAnswer":"=="
    },
    {
        "id":16,
        "question":"Which of these collections defines a LIST?",
        "answers":[
            "{\"name\": \"apple\", \"color\": \"green\"}",
            "(\"apple\", \"banana\", \"cherry\")",
            "{\"apple\", \"banana\", \"cherry\"}",
            "[\"apple\", \"banana\", \"cherry\"]"],
        "correctAnswer":"[\"apple\", \"banana\", \"cherry\"]"
    },
    {
        "id":17,
        "question":"Which of these collections defines a TUPLE?",
        "answers":[
            "{\"name\": \"apple\", \"color\": \"green\"}",
            "(\"apple\", \"banana\", \"cherry\")",
            "{\"apple\", \"banana\", \"cherry\"}",
            "[\"apple\", \"banana\", \"cherry\"]"],
        "correctAnswer":"(\"apple\", \"banana\", \"cherry\")"
    },
    {
        "id":18,
        "question":"Which of these collections defines a SET?",
        "answers":[
            "{\"name\": \"apple\", \"color\": \"green\"}",
            "[\"apple\", \"banana\", \"cherry\"]",
            "{\"apple\", \"banana\", \"cherry\"}",
            "(\"apple\", \"banana\", \"cherry\")"],
        "correctAnswer":"{\"apple\", \"banana\", \"cherry\"}"
    },
    {
        "id":19,
        "question":"Which of these collections defines a DICTIONARY?",
        "answers":[
            "{\"name\": \"apple\", \"color\": \"green\"}",
            "{\"apple\", \"banana\", \"cherry\"}",
            "(\"apple\", \"banana\", \"cherry\")",
            "[\"apple\", \"banana\", \"cherry\"]"],
        "correctAnswer":"{\"name\": \"apple\", \"color\": \"green\"}"
    },
    {
        "id":20,
        "question":"Which collection is ordered, changeable, and allows duplicate members?",
        "answers":[
            "LIST",
            "SET",
            "TUPLE",
            "DICTIONARY"],
        "correctAnswer":"LIST"
    },
    {
        "id":21,
        "question":"Which collection does not allow duplicate members?",
        "answers":[
            "SET",
            "LIST",
            "TUPLE"],
        "correctAnswer":"SET"
    },
    {
        "id":22,
        "question":"How do you start writing an if statement in Python?",
        "answers":[
            "if (x > y)",
            "if x > y then:",
            "if x > y:"],
        "correctAnswer":"if x > y:"
    },
    {
        "id":23,
        "question":"How do you start writing a while loop in Python?",
        "answers":[
            "x > y while {",
            "while x > y {",
            "while x > y:",
            "while (x > y)"],
        "correctAnswer":"while x > y:"
    },
    {
        "id":24,
        "question":"How do you start writing a for loop in Python?",
        "answers":[
            "for x > y:",
            "for each x in y:",
            "for x in y:"],
        "correctAnswer":"for x in y:"
    },
    {
        "id":25,
        "question":"Which statement is used to stop a loop?",
        "answers":[
            "exit",
            "break",
            "stop",
            "return"],
        "correctAnswer":"break"
    }
]